ONI HARNANTYO

Tangerang, Indonesia • +62 856-4355-3402 • oni.harnantyo97@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/oniharnantyo • https://github.com/oniharnantyo

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer and Squad Lead with 6+ years of experience in the fintech industry specializing in backend systems. At LinkAja, I lead the AI/ML & Fraud squad, driving cost optimization, enhancing observability, and scaling critical services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LinkAja May 2021 - Present

Squad Lead

- Led the AI/ML & Fraud squad, balancing workloads, aligning with company goals, and fostering a strong team culture through mentoring and knowledge sharing.
- Collaborated with system analysts and engineers to standardize event ingestion payloads, improving data quality and consistency across services.
- Initiated cost-saving measures by introducing more efficient tools, reducing infrastructure and operational expenses.
- Enhanced observability and monitoring by implementing the Four Golden Signals framework, improving system reliability and incident response.

Specialist Backend Engineer

- Member of the Anti-Fraud & Al/ML squad, developing services to detect and prevent fraudulent activities.
- Rewrote anti-fraud services from Java to Golang, reducing infrastructure costs by ~90%
- Expanded monitoring coverage of fraud-related events by 100%, enabling faster and more accurate fraud detection.

Senior Backend Engineer

- Contributed to the Payment squad (Cash-in & Cash-out flows) and Promotion & Loyalty unit (loyalty points, cashback, etc.), ensuring high system reliability.
- Consistently wrote clean, maintainable, and well-documented code (primarily in Golang), achieving >90% unit test coverage.
- Drove internal improvement by suggesting standardization of time data types in databases, increasing maintainability across teams.

Authscure Feb 2019 - May 2021

- Contributed to develop eVoucha, a voucher redemption system.
- Contributed to build Petronas Love Local, a platform to redeem offers from local merchant.
- Implemented Secure SDLC.

EDUCATION

Universitas Teknologi Digital Indonesia

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020

Bachelor Of Informatics Engineering - Grade: 3.91

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Skills: Golang, PostgreSQL, Redis, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, Mongo, Microservices, and Monitoring
- Languages: Indonesian and English
- Projects:
 - Vidyasena (https://vidyasena.org) Fullstack Engineer